SUKHWINDER SINGH

८+91−94170077405 **?** Noida, India

■ sukhwindernagpal@yahoo.in in singhsukhwinder13 🗘 singhhsukh 🎓 singhhsukh.github.io

Software Professional with over 7 years of experience in software development and designing large scaleable systems. Hands on experience of designing and deploying AI-driven solutions for healthcare, including chatbot creation, LLM integration, testing, and deployment.

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks:

Python[PySpark, PyTorch, TensorFlow], Django[DRF], FastAPI, Java[maven]

Cloud & DevOps:

AWS, AZURE, OCI, K8s, Docker, Jenkins PostgreSQL, Snowflake, ElasticSearch

Databases: Misc.:

Git, Databricks, Redis, Kafka

EXPERIENCE

AI Engineer (SDE-3)

Jun 2022 - Present

Techniphy

Noida, India

- Spearheaded the development and deployment of an AI-powered chatbot for a healthcare client, facilitating patient interactions for appointment scheduling and Query Resoluiton.
- Designed and implemented a **FHIR** data transformation tool to facilitate patient data access via APIs in compliance with FHIR standards. Successfully deployed the tool across multiple U.S.-based customer environments using **AWS** and **Azure**.
- Led the integration of Large Language Models to improve the fill rate and case coverage of training data set required for development and testing of FHIR data Transformation tool.

Python Developer (IC3)

March 2019 - January 2022

Oracle

Hyderabad, India

- Co-designed the **architecture** of Fusion Automation, an automation framework, using **Python with Django Rest Framework**. Played a key role in integrating **AI and ML** components to drive automation and innovation.
- Developed **ML modules** within the Fusion Automation framework to enhance failure analysis and predictive capabilities using **Python and machine learning techniques**. Focused on improving diagnostic accuracy and predictive insights.

Associate Consultant

July 2017- March 2019

Capgemini

Hyderabad, India

- Part of a team responsible for delivering customized software solutions, focusing on backend development with Java and SQL.
- Engaged in software development lifecycle activities, including requirement analysis, coding, testing, and client demos.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration(Part-time), Information Technology

2021-2023

LPU DE

Jalandhar, India

Bachelor of Technology (Full-time), Information Technology

2013 - 2017

National Institute of Technology

Jalandhar, India

AWARDS

- Recipient of Outstanding AI Solution Award in August 2023 at Technify.
- Recipient of the **Best Product award(Team)**, only awarded to Handful of Product teams in Oracle.

INTERESTS

Reading

Classic Novels, Crime and Thriller Novels, Punjabi & Urdu Poetry

Sports

Football, Cricket, Badminton